Guide to the Morris Raphael Cohen Papers 1898-1981
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Personal Papers, Papers Relating to Thomas Davidson, and Other Papers, 1898-1980
  - Jewish Social Studies; Memos of the Jewish Joint Distribution Committee and Minutes of the American Jewish Committee (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous papers of the Conference on Jewish Relations; typescript drafts of speeches by Morris Cohen to various groups (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - "What I believe as an American Jew," typescript mimeographed copies (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "King Saul's Daughter," typescript drafts (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - [Moses Moskowitz,] "Plan of a study of the Social History of Jews," typescript draft; miscellaneous notes related to history of Jews (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Papers by various authors on American Judaism (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, A, 1939-1940s (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, B (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, C (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, D (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, E (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, F (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, F (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, G (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, H (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, I (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, J (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, K (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, L (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, M (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, N (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, O (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, P (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, R (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, S (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, T (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, V (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence of Morris Cohen, Conference on Jewish Relations, W, X,Y, Z (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified Correspondence on Jewish Relations (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Cohen's correspondence (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, miscellaneous notes, memos, etc. (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Ledger of Mark David Hirsch (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, rubber stamp (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Hersh, "Comparative Criminality of the Jewish and Non-Jewish Population of Poland," typescript (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, bulletins, newsletters, etc. (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, MacDonald's Letter of Resignation (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Jewish Studies (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Cohen, student work, Physical laboratory notes (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Cohen, student work, Latin grammar (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - CCNY, Abraham, Leo, course materials on metaphysics and ethics (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - CCNY, Course syllabi, miscellaneous, Morris R. Cohen and others (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - CCNY, Edel, course materials on the philosophy of law (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - CCNY, Morris Raphael Cohen Library Building, dedication, 1958 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - CCNY, "Realism and nominalism," notes on Dewey and Peirce (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - CCNY, Russell, Bertrand, controversy over CCNY appointment (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - CCNY, Schappes defense committee, testimony of Morris R. Cohen, 1941 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - CCNY, Cohen's students' examinations, registration lists, etc. (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - CCNY, Students' papers (Box 57, Folder 9-11)
  - CCNY, Testimonial dinner honoring Cohen's 25th year at CCNY, 1927 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - CCNY, University registration lists, miscellaneous, including University of Chicago (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - CCNY, "Using wisdom," "Abstract of the paper on the background and development of legal philosophy in the Americas," authors not identified (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, B'nai B'rith, "Contributions of American Jews to the law," exhibit featuring Morris R. Cohen, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Citations, testimonials, honoring Morris R. Cohen (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Cohen Student Memorial Fund (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Clippings documenting Morris R. Cohen's activities (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Condolences on Cohen's death (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Eulogy, biographical notes (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Hair (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Photographs (Box 58, Folder 8-9)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Papers and passport, Morris R. Cohen (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Portrait, copper plate engraving (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Cohen, Abraham, estate (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Family papers and memorabilia, Cohen, Abraham, certificate of citizenship (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Biographical works, published and unpublished (Box 59, Folder 1-5)
  - Drafts, on philosophy of Morris R. Cohen (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - "Cohen's intellectual critique of American thought," Harold Blackman, draft, correspondence (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Lecture series, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - M.R. Cohen Symposium on the philosophy of law, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Society of American Philosophy, 7th annual meeting, 1980 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Conferences and lectures featuring Morris R. Cohen (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - New York Philosophical Club, 1919-1927 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, Gamma chapter (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Society of American Historians, American Philosophical Association, various other memberships (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Diplomas (see also Box 72) (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Appointment books (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
  - Pocket notebooks (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Cancelled checks, Morris and Mary Cohen (Box 62, Folder 1-5)
  - Check register, 1940-1942 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Deposit books, 1940-1941 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous receipts (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Orders for books (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Publishers' contracts, payments receipts (Box 62, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Published Works, 1902=1981
  - Clippings (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Book reviews (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Offprints, A-F (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Offprints, G-J (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Offprints, K-M (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Offprints, N-R (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Offprints, S-Z (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Galleys (Box 63, Folder 8-9)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, A-B (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, C-G (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, H-I (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, J (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, K-L (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, M-N (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, O (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, Pa-Ph (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, Pi-Pz (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, Q-R (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Journals, alphabetical by article, S-Z (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Printed works, by others than Morris R. Cohen (Box 65, Folder 5)
- Series V: Leonora Cohen Rosenfield Paper, 1904-1980
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence
    - Correspondence, A-K (Box 66, Folder 1-13)
    - Correspondence, L-Z (Box 67, Folder 1-14)
    - Cardozo, Benjamin (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Cooper, Leon (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Ducasse, C.J. (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Farrell, James T. (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Fisch, Max (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Frankfurter, Felix (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Grossman, Max (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Halpern, Philip (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Hand, Learned (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Johnson, Alvin (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Kruse, Cornelius (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Laski, Richard (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - MacDowell Colony, correspondence, draft (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Mayer, Arthur and Leo (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Morris, Charles (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Reustle, Frederick (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Santayana, George (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Shipley, Joseph (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Silverman, Hirsch (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - Smithsonian Institution, correspondence re; Einstein letters (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - Vasconcelos, Jose (Box 68, Folder 22)
    - Walcott, Gregory (Box 68, Folder 23)
    - Weiss, Paul (Box 68, Folder 24)
    - Unidentified correspondence (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 2: Material for Portrait of a philosopher - Morris R. Cohen in life letters
    - Portrait of a philosopher; Morris R. Cohen in life letters, Leonora Cohen Rosenfield, draft (Box 69, Folder 1-2)
    - Portrait of a philosopher; Morris R. Cohen in life letters, Leonora Cohen Rosenfield, notes and drafts (Box 69, Folder 3-7)
    - Bibliographies, Morris R. Cohen (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - "Dreamer's journey," correspondence (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - "Philosophy of history," draft (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Reason and nature, reviews (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Einstein, Albert, notes and drafts regarding (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, notes and drafts regarding (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Nicomachean ethics (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - "Cohen on Dewey and liberalism", draft, correspondence (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - "Days of triumph", appendix, draft (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Vignettes on the life of Morris R. Cohen (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Cohen, Morris R., memorials (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 3: Personal and professional papers
    - Rockefeller Foundation, grant proposal for biography (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Offprints, clippings (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - "Morris Cohen, the teacher", galley, drafts (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Lists; classes, committees, correspondence (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Speeches, Leonora C. Rosenfield and unidentified (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Bank accounts, cancelled checks (Box 71, Folder 6-7)
    - Rosenfield, Harry, appointment book (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Diary and keepsake wallet (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Ephemera (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Research unrelated to Morris Cohen (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Diplomas from College of the City of New York and Harvard University (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Lithograph portrait of Cohen by Joseph Margulies (Box 72, Folder 2)